WHISPERING CORRIDORS
《女高怪谈》
This is Hur Eun-Young. I can't answer the phone, so leave your message.
这里是许恩英，我现在不能接听您的电话 有事请留言
2nd year, 3rd year...
第二年，第三年……
Mrs. Park, you're still here?
朴老师，你还没走？
Had to check something.
我在查点东西
I'll be leaving soon.
我一会儿就走
Guess the new semester's keeping you busy.
新学期您一定很忙吧！
Need any help?
要帮忙吗？
I'm fine.
不用，我很好
Library
“图书馆”
Hello?
喂，你好
Eun-Young?
恩英吗？
Mrs. Park?
朴老师？
Jin-Ju is here.
真珠在这里
Jin-Ju?
真珠？
I don't know.
我不知道
What are you talking about?
你在说什么？
Jin-Ju has died for sure. But she's here.
真珠肯定已经死了，但是她还在这里
Jin-Ju's been in school for 9 years.
真珠已经在学校里九年了
Mrs. Park...
朴老师
Eun-Young? Hello?
恩英？喂？
What are you doing here?
你在做什么？
Uh?  Waiting for you.
嗯？在等你啊！
What?
什么？
What did you say?
你刚才说什么？
I was waiting for you.
我在等你
For me? Why?
我？怎么了？
Why were you waiting for me?
你等我做什么？
We're the class clerks of the week.
在一周该我们值日了
Youn Yae-Yi, trying to make me feel guilty eh?
尹洁仪，你想让我感到内疚吗？
I'm actually 15 minutes early, thanks to my mom.
多亏了我妈妈我才能早到十五分钟
Of course you're not, I'm a bit early.
当然不是啦，其实我只早到了一点点
We never promised to meet here.
我们从没约定在这里会面
You should have waited in the classroom. It's cold.
这么冷，你该在教室里等着
Empty classrooms give me the creeps, sorry...
教室里一个人也没有，我有点怕 对不起……
Stop moping.
别在这儿呆站着了
You'll jinx my chance of spending this senior year in style.
本来想毕业这一年轻松点的 怎么会跟你分一块儿，真是煞风景
Want to become a schoolgate ghost? Come on.
你想变成校门冤魂吗？来吧！
What's this?
这是些什么？
I'm not sure, only that she's possessed.
我不能肯定，只是她有点怪癖
Possessed?
怪癖？
You know, by a grade ghost. One with a low IQ though.
知道吗？被鬼附身，人就变得神经兮兮的
Were you good friends?
你们熟吗？
Does she look like she would like me?
她看起来会喜欢我吗？
Oh, I forgot to bring a rag.
噢，我忘了拿抹布了
Hey!
喂！
What...?
怎么了？
Give me that you dufus. No need to take those back up.
真是笨！把那个给我，不用再拿着到处跑了
Hurry up.
快点！
Ji-Oh.
智伍！
It is your duty as her students.
你们都是她的学生，所以……
Anyone who damages her reputation with rumors will never be forgiven.
谁也不准烂传谣言，否则就要受到处分
You heard.
听见没有？
Don't distract the other students with gossip, understand?
别跟其他的同学胡乱说，明白吗？
It's all for the best, Okay?
这样对谁都好，知道了吗？
Fortunately, we're swearing this oath of honor... ...before all hell breaks loose.
幸好把你们都叫到一块儿跟你们说明白 否则会天下大乱的
You'll all be held responsible if anything happens.
如果再发生什么事就唯你们誓问
Got it.
都知道了？
Yes sir.
是
You'll take the blame for rumors coming from Rm.3. Understood!
要是三班有什么谣言传出来就找你 听见没有？
Yes sir.
是
Why did she do it?
为什么她要这么做？
It's not clear. The police needs more leads.
不清楚，警察还在找线索
You could kill yourself for any reason... ...But why do it at school?
自杀可以有很多原因，但是为什么非要在学校里？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
The principal will assign a new homeroom teacher for Rm3.
校长会给三班安排一位新班主任
Special instructions will be given.
而且还有其它课程指示
But make sure this is kept confidential.
但是要确保机密
Hey!    Are you sure?
喂！你肯定吗？
Ever see me tell a lie?
我以前说过谎吗？
Yeah.
是啊
This is for real.
这是真的
Suicide?
自杀？
Not all suicides are by hanging. This case stinks.
并不是所有的自杀都是上吊死的 这个就糟透了
Most of the students wanted to kill old fox.
大多数学生都想那老狐狸早点死
Jin-Ju is here.
真珠在这儿
Really? For me?
真的？送给我的？
Isn't it a family heirloom? Thanks Jin-Ju.
这不是家传之宝吗？谢谢你啊，真珠
Is your Dad still drinking a lot?
你爸爸还在酗酒吗？
I don't know.
我不知道
Don't be so cold.
别这么冷冰冰的
Did you hear? Jung-Sook was the first to be here.
你听说了吗？郑淑那天第一个来到的
Yeah, and she wasn't even the clerk of the week.
是啊，而且她也不是值日生
She was there even before the clerks.
她比值日生来的还早呢
Remember last weeks shouting match with Old Fox?
你还记得上几周她跟老狐狸大呼小叫的吗？
Making out you two?
你俩在干什么？
Go work in a factory. If you can cut it?
老老实实学习，你想捣乱吗？
Or stay at home. You hear?
要不就呆在家里，听见没有？
Degenerates.
不学好
Look at your uniform. Hands out.
看看你的校服，把手伸出来
You're such a bad influence.
伤风败俗的东西
What's this smell? Incense?
什么味？烧香味？
It figures. Having a Shaman for a mother.
哎呀呀，给老妈上坟还是怎么着
Miss Hur.
许老师
A penny for your thoughts.
刚才叫了你一声了
You weren't answering.
你没回应
Oh, were you calling me?
噢，你在叫我？
You're the only teacher by that last name.
这里就你一个老师姓许
Sorry, I still feel like a student here.
不好意思，在这儿我觉得自己还像个学生
Really?
是吗？
So Mrs. Park used to be your senior homeroom teacher?
朴老师曾经也是你的毕业班主任老师？
Her death must have shocked you.
她的死一定对你影响很大
She said she had something to check. I assumed it was important.
她说她要查点东西，我想一定很重要吧？
What was she checking?
她想查什么？
I'm not sure,... ...but she was staring at her class agenda book.
不太肯定，她好像当时盯着她的班级名册……
Jin-Ju's died for sure.
真珠肯定死了
But she's here. Jin-Ju's been in school for 9 years.
但是她还在这里，真珠在学校里已经九年了
It's not you.
你肯定不是的
I just don't feel like it. So childish.
我觉得不会是，这太幼稚了
Do it on your own.
你自己看着办吧
Nobody else can call the spirits.
别人都没那个超能力的
Just this one time. Please?
求你了，就这一次
Oh mighty spirit, come to us...
无所不能的主啊，出来吧……
Draw us a circle if you are with us.
如果你听见我们就画个圆圈
Draw us a circle if she is a virgin. An X if she is not.
如果她是处女你就画个圆圈 如果她不是就画个叉
Having fun?
闹够了没有？
Get your asses over here.
你们两个该死的给我过来
What the fuck is Mad Dog doing in our class?
那疯狗又来我们班干什么？
Hasn't senior year put some sense into you?
你们脑子里面就没有“毕业年级”这个概念
If you're so psychic, make a living out of it.
你有超能力，就变堆钱出来啊？
Why bother with school?
还待在学校里干啥？
I asked her for my grades.
我问她功课的事
Lim Ji-Oh, are you a Shaman or a witch doctor?
林智伍，你是巫婆？还是道士？
Then get better grades. You're lowering the class average.
多考点分数，班里的平均分都让你拖累了
Get out of my sight.
回去吧
Who is it?
谁啊？
Who's the smart ass who just laughed?
刚才谁在那儿鬼笑？
I see... Everyone on your desks, now.
我看，现在你每个人都给我跪桌子上
I'll teach you a lesson.  Arms up!
我得好好的教你们一课，举起手来！
Can't you greet your new homeroom teacher with respect?
你们不向你们的新班主任表示敬意吗？
Homeroom teacher?
班主任？
Due to personal matters, Mrs. Park is unable to continu her duties.
由于个人原因，朴老师不能继续任职了
I will be taking over,... you hear?
我会接替她的工作，听见没有？
This means two things.
这就意味着两件事
One, a better chance at getting into college.
第一，你们都有机会上大学了
Two, no personal life for a year.
第二，整整一年都别想再有业余活动
The new semester of your senior year... is getting you somewhat excited...
毕业年的新学期，会给你们带来新的竞争……
I advise you to get rid of such cheap sentimentalisms.
我建议你们最好不要这么感情用事
They're luxuries a senior should do without.
对于应届毕业生来说更应该杜绝
Got it!
你们都听见了！
My motto is: KEEP YOUR OWN PLACE.
我的格言就是：自己管好自己
This will be the class motto from now on.
从现在开始就是你们所有人的格言
You're each other's rival,... but frankly speaking you're each other's enemy.
你们相互之间都是竞争者 说白了就是敌人
The worst enemy in war is yourself. You CAN defeat your inner enemy.
最大的敌人就是你们自己，你必须战胜你自己
You can be a winner.
然后你就是最后的胜利者
I've re-scheduled the exercise exams for tomorrow. Be prepared.
明天我准备了模拟测验，大家都准备一下
Get used to it and stop whining!
你们要学会适应，而不是抱怨
It's for evaluation purposes, so relax.
只是摸摸底，别担心
If you don't have what it takes, tough.
也别拿着当儿戏
Class dismissed. Start cleaning up.
课就到此结束，开始打扫卫生吧
Dang, wish we had exams every day.
该死的，以后看来是要天天考试了
What?
什么？
Then school ends early.
放学可也就早了
Bitch, exams never kept you from leaving early.
白痴，只要有考试你就别想早走
You're always the first to dive outta da classroom.
你总是第一个出教室
It's better to chill after the exams...
那总比考完了心情沮丧的要好
Bullshit!
该死的！
Ow, ouch.
哦，疼死了
Stuck?
怎么了？
Aw, fuck. It's blocked.
啊，妈的，塞住了
Didn't we get pierced on the same day?
我们不是一天穿的吗？
Ouch.
疼啊！
Stop whining bitch. ...see it's going in.
别叫唤了，看，进去了
Stop it, it hurts.
住手，弄疼了
I'm trying to take it out you slut. Want a bloody slit up your nose?
妈的，我正帮你弄出来 你想在鼻子上留条口子吗？
Hey!
哎！
Whatcha lookin at?
你看什么看？
Huh, are you ignoring me?
哼，你没看见我在这儿吗？
What's all the fuss?
吵什么吵？
You psychic, mind your own business!
喂，神经病，管好你自己的事
Hur Eun-Young
许恩英
I'll ask them to replace the missing yearbooks.
我会叫他们补上那本丢失的年册的
So you're an alumni.
老师你也是校友吗？
How did you know?
你怎么知道的？
You were pretty famous as the student with looks and brains.
在你们那届学生当中 你可是出了名的美貌与智慧并重啊
My grades were so so, and the yearbook shows prettier girls.
我的学习成绩一般，年册上有更多漂亮的女孩
Why did you choose to be a teacher?
你为什么当老师？
I guess it's not so bad after all.
我想毕竟老师还是一份不错的职业吧
Can I drop the formalities when we're alone?
当我们单独在一块的时候我们能像朋友一样吗？
If you insist.
当然！
The teachers often compare us together.
老师常常拿我们学生作比较
But they say I'm prettier and smarter.
可是他们说我比较聪明漂亮
You're definitely prettier, but do you also get good grades?
你确实很漂亮，但是学习行吗？
Yes, I'm applying for Seoul National University.
是的，我正在申请首尔国立大学
What major?
什么专业？
Does it matter? After all, it's the best.
管他呢，反正是最好的
There must be something that interests you.
你肯定有些感兴趣的东西
Nothing special. Besides I hate studying.
没什么特别的，包括学习在内
Once I get admitted, I'm done with books.
只要我的申请一通过，我就不用再看这些书了
An SNU degree is a gold card for everything.
首尔国立大学的学位证书那可是一块金字招牌
Even with an SNU degree, it wouldn't hurt reading Joyce.
就算是拿了首尔国立大学的学位证 读读乔伊斯・詹姆斯的书也不错啊
How come you're still here? Aren't you going home?
你怎么还在这儿？你不是回家了吗？
I didn't have the chance...to thank you in the toilet.
我还没机会谢谢你呢，关于在厕所里的那件事
You like to do girly things, don't you?
你真和纯情少女似的
Thanks anyway.
不管怎么说，谢谢了
Have a seat.
做啊！
Practicing for art school?
你准备上艺术院校吗？
Nope. I'm supposed to have no talent...
不会了，我想我没那个天赋
How would you know?
你自己怎么知道？
My mom said...it's a waste of time.
我妈说过，那简直就是浪费时间
She's right.
看来她是正确的
This is just for fun.
只不过是画着玩玩罢了
Can I see...?
我能看看吗？
?!...No. It's embarrassing.
还是别了，画得又不好
I guess it is embarrassing.
我猜你是怕丢人吧？
You're breaking my heart. Okay, I'll show it to you.
行了，别挖苦我了，好，给你看看吧
I told you so.
早告诉过你了
Why paint something so scary?
为什么画上的东西这么恐怖
School can be a horrific experience... for both students and teachers.
学校生活本来就是一次恐怖行程 不管是对学生还是对老师来说
Like witnessing a tragic death.
就像是目睹车祸现场
Do you get it?
你能明白吗？
I guess that's why I can't erase... the image of Old Fox from my head.
我想这就是我为什么挥不去老狐狸的影子
It's like an inspiration.
就像是神灵感应
Terrific.
棒极了！
What is?
什么？
You are. You speak like an artist.
你说起话来简直像艺术家
You're kidding. I can't even paint.
别开玩笑了，我都不会画画
Of course you can. You need to improve your skills...
当然你可以的，你只是需要一些绘画的技巧
...but you know how to control light.
比如怎样控制光亮度
Bad paintings drain the life out of their objects...
烂作品使生活脱离了现实
...because they lack this quality.
因为它们缺乏这些本质性的东西
This painting has it. You have a good eye for things,
这幅画就有，你对事物看得很透彻
the most important element to be a good painter.
这对一个画家来说是最重要的一点
You must have studied painting.
你是不是以前学过画
A bit.
一点点了
When? In Junior high?
什么时候，初中？
Something like that. I quit though.
差不多吧，不过中途退出了
No talent like you know who.
你很有这方面的天赋啊
Jae-Ji, will you teach me how to paint?
洁仪，你能教我画画吗？
You can join me when you get bored of teaching.
你只是读书读累了指点我一下就行了
No?
不行吗？
I...
不是……
Is it a yes or no?
到底行还是不行？
Allright, if you insist. Promise that you do as I say.
好吧，不过，以后我怎么说你怎么做
Now you sound like Mad Dog. We're mortal enemies.
你就像那疯狗老师似的，我们可是死敌啊
Don't tell me your his niece?
你不是他的外甥女吧？
Isn't this great Jin-Ju?
真珠，这记号够大吧？
Miss Hur.
许老师
What are you doing at my desk?
你在我桌子上做什么？
Is this your desk?
这是你的座位？
Yes.
是的
What brings you to our classroom?
你怎么到我们教室里来了？
This used to be my senior year homeroom. Brings back memories.
这曾经是我毕业那一年待过的教室 坐在这想起了过去的一些事
It's still pretty much the same.
简直和从前一样
I didn't do that.
那不是我刻的
I know...I did it.
我知道……是我刻的
Was this your desk?
您以前也是在这张桌子上
No, it was my friend's,... Jin-Ju's.
不适，是我好朋友的，真珠的
Excuse me.
打扰您很抱歉
Jin-Ju, this will be your desk forever.
真珠，这桌子永远是你的了
Here.
给
I found her address in my diary. I want to meet her family.
我在我的日记本里找到了她的地址 我想见见她的家人
I explain later. It's really important that you find it.
过会儿我再解释，你发现的确实很重要
I'll drop by later to get it. Bye mom.
挂了电话我就去拿，再见，妈妈
Looking for an old flame?
寻找旧情人吗？
No, a girlfriend from high school.
不是，我高中时候的一个好朋友
Lost touch after graduation?
毕业之后就失去联络了？
Kind of.
是的
Can't call that friendship.
那还有什么友情可言？
Guess it happens when you're busy.
工作这么忙怎么还想着这档子事儿
She died in high school.
高中的时候她就死了
Oh the student who committed suicide? Was she your friend?
噢，就是自杀的那个，她是你朋友
Yes you were in Mrs. Park's class.
对了，你在朴老师的班上
But why are you looking for her family?
但是你又为什么找她的家人
Just curious.
只是有些好奇
Go to the school storage room.
那就去学校的仓库吧
Her ghost haunts the place. You'll get to meet her in person.
她的鬼魂还徘徊在那个地方 说不定你去了还能见到她
A couple of girls claim they've seen the ghost.
两个女学生还说见到过鬼呢
She died in the art room. It used to be the art room.
她在美术教室死的 当时那里曾是美术教室
She must have jinxed the place.
她一定是霸占了那个地方
Construction workers have been sick or hurt.
建筑工人非病即伤
That's why they can't tear down the place.
所以他们都不敢拆除那些房子
Of all the places to die why choose school?
死在哪里不好，为什么非要死在学校里？
Lim Ji-Oh, you piece of shit!
林智伍，你他妈的搞什么鬼？
The vp almost had a heart attack when he found this in the art room.
副校长在美术教室发现这画差点犯心脏病
How would you explain this?
你说说这到底是怎么回事？
Answer me! Are you trying to fuck with me?
回答我，你想耍我吗？
No sir.
没有
Don't bullshit me!
没有个屁！
You degenerate.
你个混蛋！
You must be a psycho, a maniac. Some parents you must have.
你个神经病，疯子
Letting you create such a monstrosity.
你父母送你上学就是叫你画这么个怪物吗？
Get out of my sight. You disgust me!
马上出去，简直令我作呕
Go.
滚
Go! Go!
滚，混蛋
Go! Go! Go!
滚！滚！滚！
I dare you.
你还敢？
You psycho.
你个神经病！
You wanna die?
你找死吗？
Die! Die! You filth...
去死！去死！垃圾……
I told your mom not to worry.
我告诉你妈不用担心了
She's sensitive about your first exam as a senior.
她非常重视你高三的第一次考试
If you have finished, I would like to excuse...
如果没有其它的事情我想……
What's the hurry?
你急什么？
I should get back to my books.
我还要回去拿我的课本
Don't be a stranger to your own teacher.
不要见了你老师就像见了陌生人似的
A woman should be like cotton candy. Understand?
女人要学会温顺，明白吗？
So-Young.
素英
So-Young. Do you know where I can find that painting of your classmate's?
素英，你知道你同学画的那幅画上哪儿去了？
It must've been trashed. Mad Dog chewed it to pieces.
肯定成垃圾了，那疯狗都把它咬成了碎片
Mad Dog?
疯狗？
I apologize. That's what we call Mr. Oh.
抱歉，我们都是那么叫吴老师的
Shouldn't it be pervert?
那不是很变态吗？
Who's painting is it?
那画是谁画的？
Lim Ji-Oh...
林智伍
I see...
噢……
It's for the best. No more painting for me..
这也倒好，再也不用画画了
Giving up painting?
你要放弃吗？
Nowhere to paint.
没地方画画了
There's one place. The teachers will never know.
倒是有一个地方，老师肯定不会知道
Never mind.
算了
What?
怎么了
Let's go.
我们走
Where? I was just joking.
哪里？我只是随便说说的
You can't go there.
那个地方你不能去
Why not?
为什么我不能去？
It's a mess, cobwebs and rats.
那里很脏，到处都是蜘蛛网，还有老鼠什么的
We'll just take a look.
我们只是去看一看而已
Are you nuts? The place is haunted.
你疯了吗？那地方闹鬼！
Then stay here. I'll check for ghosts, okay?
那你就在这儿吧，我去会一会鬼
Who taught you to smoke?
谁教你抽烟的？
No one. Ever see me learn from anyone?
没人教，你看见我跟别人学了吗？
How brave of you. Even the teachers are scared of this place.
你胆子倒是不小，这个地方老师都不敢来
I prefer ghosts.
我喜欢鬼魂
Besides, didn't you know. I'm one myself.
对了，你不知道吗，我就一个人在这里
So is this that infamous place?
这就是那个众所周知的地方
Then lend me some space. I need a place to paint.
借我块空地，我要找个地方画画
I've been banned from the art room.
我已经被禁止去美术教室了
Don't you want to kill him?
你难道不想宰了他吗？
Yeah, why don't you do the honors?
想啊！为什么你不去完成这个壮举？
You have to pay rent. Finders keepers you know.
你得交租金，我先发现这个地方 这地方自然就是我的
Plus I'll keep my mouth shut.
另外，我会保密的
Rent?
租金？
Aren't you supposed to be a rich bitch?
你不是他妈的很有钱吗？
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
I came to ask you something and the door was open.
我想来问您点事情，我来的时候门就开着
It's okay. Have a seat.
没关系，请坐
Miss Hur, no need to feel guilty.
许老师，不用这么拘束
Wow,... someone did quite a number on this.
哇……有人在这画上花了不少功夫
Why bring it here?
为什么拿这个来？
I was curious. But the faculty lounge...
我有点奇怪，这个教师办公室……
It is uncomfortable there.
令人不舒服，是吗？
I guess I still feel like a student.
我想我还跟学生似的
Think so? Perhaps it's more than that.
你这样想？或许不止如此吧
Do you usually sketch student faces?
你经常为学生素描吗？
I like their expressions.
我喜欢她们的表情
Didn't you have something to ask?
你不是有事情要问吗？
Uh...about this painting.
嗯……关于这幅画
Hello there.
噢，你来了，在那边
You were saying.
你刚才说……
I was in the art club when I was in high school.
我上高中的时候是美术社团的
So you used to paint.
那你经常画画了
No, I sculpted faces in plaster.
不是，我是用石膏雕刻的
Sculpted?
雕刻？
I used to do friend's faces as a hobby.
只是兴趣爱好，我常常雕刻朋友们的脸
Must have been a great gift.
那是一件很不错的礼物
I hope they were.
我也这么认为
Excuse me.
打扰了
Just a moment, Ji-Oh.
等一下，智伍
Here.
给
Take it.
拿着吧
Don't give up painting.
别放弃绘画
Class motto: KEEP YOUR PLACE
班级格言：管好你自己
Park So-Young. School rank, 1st place.
朴素英，班级排名，第一
Go ahead and give her a big hand.
上前面来，鼓掌啊
Kim Jung-Sook.
金晶淑
Your class rank is 2nd place, yet your school rank is 25th.
你班里排第二，校里排第25
What's the use of studying long hours if you're not paying attention.
看书不用心，光在那儿靠时间有什么用
If you don't have the brains, ask So-Young for some tips.
要是自己没脑子，跟素英要点
Class head.
班长
Yes.
是
Hand them out after I'm gone. Dismissed!
我走了之后把这些发下去，解散！
Attention.
起立
Don't bother.
不用了
How can the class with the school's best student have the worst score?
学校里最好的学生都在这个班，但是成绩却最差
Don't greet me until you improve the class average, you hear!
成绩提不上去以后就不要敬礼了，听见了吗？
Do you have Mrs. Park's class agenda book?
请问你有朴老师的班级名册吗？
No, but perhaps the PE teacher would know.
没有，可能体育老师知道
Night patrolling with female teachers...
晚上和女老师一块儿巡逻……
...the perfect solution for lonely nights.
真是消除寂寞的最好方法
What do you think? Not bad eh?
怎么样？还不错吧？
What's wrong?
怎么了？
Too much dust. Look.
看，到处都是土
You have a vain side to you, don't you?
看来你也有虚荣的一面，不是吗？
Aren't you scared of this place? Ghosts and all...
在这里你一点都不害怕吗？有鬼啊什么的
On the contrary, I feel at ease. Like home.
恰恰相反，我感到很轻松，就像在家里一样
Really?
真的吗？
Why? Don't you?
怎么了？你不觉得吗？
Anything you say.
不是啊，和你一样啦！
Strange.
奇怪
God damn it!
该死的！
What the...ow!
他妈的怎么回事？
Who's there?
谁在那儿？
Who are you?
你是谁？
Order.
静一静！
I'll be filling in for Mr. Oh today. So behave.
今天我替吴老师代课，大家规矩点
He didn't come in today?
今天他不来了！
Is anything wrong?
发生了什么事？
How should I know?
我怎么知道？
Kim Nuri.
金璐丽
Choi An-Nat...
崔安娜……
Here.
到
He must have fallen asleep in the sauna.
他一定是洗桑拿的时候睡着了
Nothing can wake you there.
在那里什么都叫不醒你的
You think a ghost got him?
你认为他见鬼了？
Kim Yung-Sook, Kim Yung-Sook.
金晶淑，金晶淑
Is that her seat?
那是她的座位吗？
Yes Sir.
是的
Is she absent or late?
她逃课还是迟到？
She hasn't come in yet.
她还没来呢
What gives? She's never late.
怎么回事？她从来不迟到的
It was Mad Dog's turn. The ghost got him.
轮到那疯狗了，鬼缠上他了
I'm positive.
我肯定
Where did you get that from?
你从哪儿听说的？
Do I still look like your friend?
我们还是好朋友吗？
Hey...
喂……
Stop it.
住手
Look, isn't that Jung-Sook?
看，那不是晶淑吗？
I'm sure he was killed last night.
我肯定昨晚他被杀了
What makes you think so?
为什么你这么认为？
I feel it. Just like the day Old Fox died.
凭我的直觉，就像是那天老狐狸死的时候一样
I feel like I killed Mad Dog myself.
我觉得是我亲手杀了他
You think I was possessed...and murdered Mad Dog?
你是不是觉得我着魔了？是我杀了那疯狗？
Whoever did it, aren't you glad that he's gone?
不管是谁干的，他走了你不是很高兴吗？
Look, I'm not joking. I'm serious.
听着，我不是开玩笑，我是认真的
What if I'm really possessed...?
要是我真的着魔了该怎么办呐？
Ji-Oh, don't be so serious.
智伍，别这么紧张了
Don't worry. He's a die-hard. He must be playing hooky.
别担心了，他怎么会这么容易就死的呢？ 他一定是旷工了
Do as I say Eun-Young. You'll thank me one day.
我说恩英啊，总有一天你会感激我的
You won't regret it. You need to choose your friends.
你不用感到难过，应该选择别的朋友
She's no good for you.
她不适合你
Looking for this?
在找这个吗？
Yes...
是……
What for?
找这个干什么？
It's only going to depress you.
这只会让你心情低落
NAME; LIM JI-OH
姓名：林智伍
EVALUATION NOTES
“评语”
LACKS THE ABILITY AND WILL TO APPLY FOR COLLEGE
“缺乏能力报考大学”
Oh, it's you So-Young.
噢，是素英啊！
Any problems?
有什么事情吗？
No,... nothing.
噢，没有
Did you say there were spare yearbooks?
你曾说过年册都有备份的？
No, they suddenly disappeared. So stupid.
没了，它们都突然不见了，真该死
So typical of the school system.
学校里经常这样子
Have you found the painting?
你找到那幅画了吗？
Huh?
啊？
Of Ji-Oh's. You wanted to see it.
智伍，你不是想找的吗？
Oh yes, I did. Do you know Ji-Oh well?
哦，是啊，我找到了，你对智伍熟吗？
Not much. She sits next to me.
不是很了解，她就在我旁边
Why?
怎么啦？
Nothing special, apart from her ability to call the spirits.
没什么特别的，不过她能呼神唤鬼
Call the spirits?
呼神唤鬼？
Probably her way of getting attention.
或许是为了引起大家的注意吧？
If you're so curious, she's in the store room, painting...
要是你好奇就去学校仓库找她吧，她在那里画画
What's this noise?
什么声音？
What are you doing?
你干什么？该死的
Get your ass over here.
你给我过来！
Now. I said now!
过来，我说立即过来！
What brings you here?
你到这儿来干什么？
So now you're following me.
你在跟踪我？
Forget it.
得了得了
I have nothing against you. Never avoided you either.
我又没冒犯你，你怎么老缠着我
Let's just say we're different.
只能说我们是不同类的
Meet me after evening studies.
下了晚自习来找我
Why?
为什么？
Can't we talk now?
现在说不行吗？
Is your sister coming to pick you up?
那是你姐姐来接你的吗？
Sister?
姐姐？
Sorry, was that your stepmother?
对不起，那是你继母？
She looks so young.
她看起来很年轻
Kim Jung-Sook,...
金晶淑
mind your own business.
管好你自己的事情
Is your real mom still in the looney bin?
你妈不是在精神病院吗？
Bitch. To think I took pity on you.
狗娘养的，别以为我会可怜你
You think you could beat me? Guess again.
你以为你会赢过我吗？妄想吧！
You don't have what it takes. We're different.
你没那个资质，我们是不同的
Got it...? Loser!
知道了吗？婊子
Your Mother will save you. After all she's a shaman.
你妈妈会救你的，毕竟她是个巫师
I never spread those rumors about your mom.
我从来没散布你妈妈的谣言
It was Mrs. Park who told me.
那都是朴老师告诉我的
I was scared of being ostracized for taking your side.
我担心，要是偏袒你的话会被同学排斥
I never thought that anything bad would happen...
我从没想到会发生那些事，真的
She threatened to expel you for my sake, if I kept seeing you...
要是我继续见你，她就强迫你退学
I was afraid.
我很害怕
I'm so sorry Jin-Ju.
对不起，真珠
TO MY BEST FRIEND, EUN-YOUNG, FROM JIN-JU
致我最好的朋友：恩英，真珠留
Does it look like you Jin-Ju? Don't ever loose it.
像你吗？真珠，别弄坏了啊
I told you I'm Ji-Oh.
我告诉过你了，我是智伍
Then where did you get those bells?
那你是从哪里弄到这铃铛的
A friend gave them to me.
一个朋友给我的
Jin-Ju is dead.
真珠已经死了
This is where she died 9 years ago. I saw her body with my own eyes.
真珠九年前就是在这里死的，我亲眼看见的
She couldn't have given those bells to you.
她不可能把这铃铛给你
What are you talking about? These are from Jae-Yi. Yoon Jae-Yi.
你在说什么啊？这原来是洁仪的，尹洁仪
What's wrong? What happened?
怎么了？发生什么事？
TO MY BEST FRIEND, JIN-JU, FROM EUN_YOUNG, 89
致我最好的朋友：真珠，恩英留。89年
We used to be close during our freshman year.
高一的时候我们是要好的朋友
We would share our most private secrets.
最保密的事情都让对方知道
The teachers started comparing us and we drifted apart.
老师开始拿我们两个作评比 后来我们就分开了
She became distant,...
她变得冷漠了……
I never reached out to her...
我再也不能接近她了
But...
可是……
But, I never thought... It would come to this.
可是，我从没想过会变成这样
It's all my fault.
都是我的错
KANG HYUN-JOO
康贤珠
PARK JI-SUNG
朴智成
You should never have returned.
你不该回来的
EUN-YOUNG HAS RETURNED AS A TEACHER
“恩英当老师又回来了”
ONCE AGAIN MRS. PARK HAS BECOME THE HOMEROOM TEACHER
“朴老师又成了班主任”
JI-OH HASN'T DESERTED ME
“智伍没抛弃我”
You're not Jae-Yi, nor are you Jin-Ju.
你不是洁仪，而且也不是真珠
You're not Eun Young.
你不是恩英
I've always been and still am Eun-Young.
我是恩英，过去是，现在也是
You can never be the old Eun-Young.
你不是以前的恩英了
You'll become just like Old Fox.
你会变得像老狐狸一样
You're wrong.
不是
I'm still Jin-Ju's friend, Eun-Young.
我仍然是真珠的朋友，恩英
It's no use now.
现在说什么也没用了
I don't want to hurt you,
我不想伤你
but I don't have a choice.
但是我别无选择
Jae-Yi.
洁仪
You could never kill me.
你不能杀我
Without you, I can continu being a student.
要不是你，我还会继续上学的
Stop it...
别说了
What good would it do? You're a ghost, not a student anymore!
那又能怎么样，你现在是鬼魂 再也不可能是学生了
At first, I just wanted to have a yearbook.
最初，我只想要一本年册
But then I wanted more. I needed a friend...
但是后来我想得到更多 我需要一个朋友
who really understood and cared about me...
她能真正理解和关心我
But not this way!
但不是通过这种方式
You're not human!
你不是人！
I only had to keep the classroom full, like these desks.
我只得让教室满满的，就像那些课桌一样
Nothing more.
仅此而已
For the past 9 years, no one suspected my identity.
九年以来，没有人怀疑我的身份
Nobody cared if I was there or not.
没人关心我是不是在那儿
Whether I was human or not, it didn't matter.
不管我是不是人，那都不重要
I just had to fill the empty seats,...
我只是想填满所有的空座位
and be there during headcounts.
点名的时候都在那儿
I understand.
我理解
But you have to stop now.
但是现在你要住手了
You don't get it now that you're a teacher...
你不会理解的，因为你是老师……
What happened to you will never happen again.
过去发生的事情都不会再发生了
It always has and always will.
不会的，现在、将来都会发生
Trust me Jin-Ju. I'll do my best.
相信我，真珠，我会尽力的
I will. Trust me.
我会的，相信我
There's only so much a teacher can do.
你一个老师毕竟能力有限
Stop it Jae-Yi. Stop!
住手，洁仪，住手！
I don't care if you're a ghost or not.
我不在意你是不是鬼魂
But you've gone too far this time.
但是这次你太离谱了
Don't worry Ji-Oh. Everything will go back to normal.
智伍，没事的，所有的事情都会好起来的
We can never...go back.
我们永远都不能回头了
Don't worry Ji-Oh.
别担心，智伍
You have to stop.
你得住手了
I can't let you continu harming the teachers, for my sake.
有我在，我不会让你伤害老师的
I've waited so long for you.
我已经等了这么长时间了
I can't give up now.
我是不会放弃的
Stop!
住手！
It's no use Ji-Oh.
那没用的，智伍
Lay a finger on her and I'm gone.
你载触犯她，我就死给你看
Stop the horrors. I can understand you now.
别再行凶了，我现在能完全理解你
But the bloodshed has to end.
这场流血事件必须结束了
So many things I wanted to do.
这么多事情我想去做
I pined for a friend... who would reach out to me...
我渴望有一个能帮助我的朋友……
Now I've met that friend...
现在我已经找到了……
I love you too,...really.
我也很喜欢你，真的
But please stop... Leave the rest to us.
但是求你住手，放过我们其他人吧
Rest in peace Jae-Yi.
好好安息吧，洁仪
I never intended to hurt anyone. I just wanted a friend...
我从没想过要伤害任何人 我只是想要一个朋友
and leave with good memories. That's all...
留下一些美好的回忆，仅此而已
I can't stay like this,...
我不会再这样下去了
cause I'm not human.
因为我毕竟不是人
I'm so sorry.
对不起
We'll never forget you.
我们不会忘记你的